

DE VITERBO, MARTY

GitHub: https://github.com/mmdeviterbo

Email: mmdeviterbo@up.edu.ph

Summary

A web developer specializing back end and moreover front-end development. Experienced and well-versed in programming languages and/or technologies such as ReactJS, NextJS, ExpressJS/NodeJS, Python, Java, C, SQL, and MongoDB. Lead as a project manager and team leader in previous projects, strong background in project management and has best relations with both co-developer and client.

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Technology Adaptability
- Creative design and animation
- Complex problem solver
- Innovative
- UI/UX Frameworks

Experience

Developer | January 2022 to May 2022

ElBids: Online Auction System

- https://elbids.vercel.app/
- Develop (as a solo) an online auction system for UPLB stakeholders
- Utilize the latest technologies: NextJS, Apollo-GraphQL, NodeJS, MaterialUI

Software Engineer Intern | June 2021 to August 2021

Dashlabs.ai | Simplifying Healthcare

- https://www.dashlabs.ai/
- Full-stack debugging
- Improve the system by joining the Software Quality Assurance (QA) Team using Jest
- Improve and develop front-end interface

Project Manager | April 2021 to June 2021

UPLB Institute of Computer Science Online Library System

- https://deviterbo-library.netlify.app/
- Team up with developers to create elegant interfaces, friendly interactions, and experiences.
- Develop and organize project optimal workflow of the system
- Work and lead with talented developer to manage complex design system
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end as well as efficiency on back-end side program
- Implement quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability of the system

Front end Team Leader | January 2020 to December 2020

Hotel Management System

- A volunteer work to develop user interface that is particularly suited with low-level of knowledge on using a computer
- Manage to handle the technology or frameworks to have a consistency in the interface
- Prioritize and implement mobile responsiveness application

Python Developer | August 2018 to December 2018

Checkers (Dama Boardgame)

- Recreate the checkers boardgame using Python
- Optimize the game with faster running time
- Output correct logs during the game

Membership and Internals Affair Member | 1/2019 to present

Alliance of Computer Science Students

• Increased efficiency and performance by monitoring team member productivity and providing feedback. Organizing and leading major events of the organization.

Publication Committee Member | 1/2019 to present

UP Munscials Alumni Society

 Enhanced publication design initiatives while managing effective marketing campaigns. Created trend boards, investigated recommended strategic adoptions to capitalize on projected changes

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science | University of the Philippines, Los Baños

2018-2022

Magna Cum Laude with eight consecutives in achieving university scholar maintaining GPA of above 1.5

High School Diploma | Muntinlupa Science Highschool

2012 - 2018

Two consecutives in achieving high-honors on K-12 curriculum with average of 97

Languages

Tagalog

Primary

English

Secondary